

Ondrej Moriš

Summary

In my academic life at Masaryk University I was broadly interested in algorithm engineering with a particular interest in route-planning algorithms and combinatorics. In my professional life I am a quality assurance engineer of Red Hat Enterprise Linux. My work is focused on tests automation of components related to the security and government certifications (FIPS 140 & Common Criteria). I am skilled in Linux system administration, C/C++ programming and shell scripting. I have working experience with Java, minor working experience with Python and a moderate understanding of C#, Scala, Go and markup languages.

Education

2010–2012 RNDr. in Computer Science, Faculty of informatics, Masaryk University, Brno.

Field of Study: Informatics. Supervised by doc RNDr. Petr Hliněný, Ph.D.

Thesis: Practical Route Planning Algorithms

2008–2010 Master in Computer Science, Faculty of informatics, Masaryk University, Brno.

Field of Study: Informatics - Computer Systems.

Thesis: Efficient Route Planning in Huge Graphs With Limited Resources

2005–2008 Bachelor in Computer Science, Faculty of informatics, Masaryk University, Brno.

Field of Study: Applied Informatics (Parallel and Distributed Systems, Comp. Systems & Security).

Thesis: Route Planning for Huge Graphs

2013 Winter School on Algorithms, Beroun, Czech Republic.

The University of Warwick (UK) and West Bohemia (CZE), December 12 - 15, 2013

2011 Summer School on Mobile Phone Programming, Aalborg Universitet, Denmark.

July 22 - August 15, 2011

2011 Block Course on Methods in Graph Drawing, Technische Universität Berlin, Germany.

March 22 - April 8, 2011

2008, 2009 Spring School on Combinatorics, Rokytnice nad Jizerou, Borová Láda, Czech Republic.

Annual two weeks international spring school sessions organized by Charles University

Employment

2009– now **Senior Quality Assurance Engineer**, Red Hat Czech, s.r.o., Brno.

Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Base OS - Security and Government Certifications

2012 **GSOC** - **Student Developer**, Google, Inc. & TU Dortmund, Germany.

Google Summer of Code, Open Graph Drawing Framework

Implemented hypergraph drawing layout into OGDF (the certificate of completion awarded)

2008 **Open Source Developer**, SUSE Linux & Faculty of informatics, Masaryk University.

Linux Projects summer program

Sound preprocessing in Twinkle (double scholarship awarded)

2007–2008 Java Developer, Unicorn, a.s. & Vigour, a.s., Brno.

Banking information system development

	Teaching & Supervising	
2008–2014	Seminar Assistant, Faculty of informatics, Masaryk University, Brno. Mathematical Foundations of Computer Science, e-learning & seminar tutor	
2011–2015 (expected)	Supervising bachelor students, Masaryk University & Brno University of Technology. Practical Route Planning Algorithms (2011), Route Planning With Restrictions (2013), Automated Tests Execution in Libreswan (ongoing) Awards & Certifications	
October 2011	MEMICS 2011 , Doctoral Workshop on Mathematical and Engineering Methods in CS. Generalized Maneuvers in Route Planning (with Petr Hliněný), best paper award	
May 2008	SVOČ 2008 , Czech & Slovak University Students' Scientific Competition. Applied informatics, awarded second prize	
May 2013	Red Hat Certified Security Specialist. Certificate Number: 100-183-078	
May 2013	Red Hat Certified Virtualization Administrator , <i>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization 3.1</i> . Certificate Number: 100-183-078	
•	Red Hat Certified Engineer, Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6. Certificate Number: 100-183-078	
March 2011	Red Hat Certified System Administrator , <i>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5 and 6</i> . Certificate Number: 100-183-078	
June 2009	IBM Certified Solution Designer , Rational Unified Process v7.0. Certificate Number: PR1093871	
	Technical Skills	
C/C++, Java	Advanced	Shell Scripting Avanced
Python, C#	Basics	TEX, HTML Intermediate
Scala, Go	Basics	UNIX/Linux Advanced
Advanced	working experience	
Intermediate	no working experience, understanding and writing any code	
Basics	no or minor working experience, understanding any code, writing simple programs	

Language Skills

Slovak, Czech Native CEF Level C2

English **Full professional proficiency** CEF Level B2

French Elementary proficiency CEF Level A1

Interests

Professional Problem Solving, Algorithm Engineering, Beautiful Algorithms and Combinatorics Personal Bodybuilding, Running, Squash, Hiking, Football, Reading, Cinema and Theatre